friendlyatheist.com 2019-12-27

# Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is a part of the [ **Terms of Use**](http://www.patheos.com/Terms-of-Use.html)[ ** **](http://www.patheos.com/Terms-of-Use.html) and forms a part of the legal agreement you have with BN Media, LLC (also referred to below as "BN Media," "us," "we" or "our") concerning your use of our Site. Any term that is not defined in this Privacy Policy shall have the meaning set forth in our Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform and notify you about our policies concerning the use of information we collect, maintain and use in connection with your use of our Site, whether or not you register to become a Member.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, because even if you do not register or become a Member, by using our Site, using, downloading or installing any related software, services, and/or content available from or through our Site (or attempting to do any of these) it means that you agree to be bound by and comply with this Privacy Policy and our [ **Terms of Use**](http://www.patheos.com/Terms-of-Use.html). In general, you can visit or browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. 

**Changes to this Privacy Policy:**  We have the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time by posting an updated version on our Site, without advance notice to you. The changes shall be effective to you immediately upon posting. We encourage you to check this Privacy Policy often so you are and remain aware of the terms and conditions that apply to you.

**Personal Information/Postings:**  We respect the privacy needs and concerns of Site users. We are committed to protecting our users' privacy and keeping Personal Information you share with us through the use of our Site secure. However, you understand, acknowledge and agree that we do not and cannot control your Member Content, including Postings, nor are or shall we be liable if you post or make any information, including Member Content, available to others on our Site or otherwise. When we use the term "Personal Information" we mean information such as your first/middle initial or name and last name, street address, town or city, state, zip code, telephone number, your date of birth, email address, gender, wireless or mobile number, phone number, faith tradition and any other information that would allow someone to identify you or contact you that you provide to us. Purchases made through the Site require that you supply your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, credit card number or other billing information.

**General Information Collected by the Site (What Data Do We Collect)**

We may collect general browsing and preferences information on the Site, which allows for more appropriate and effective advertising presentation for you. We may also aggregate the data from all of the users' browsing sessions, and use or sell that aggregate data to a third party. None of that data includes Personal Information as defined in this Privacy Policy. Individual Users may opt-out of having their browsing data collected by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance's consumer choice page at:  **<http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>**

**Billing and Credit Card Information**

To enable payment, we collect and store billing and credit card information. This information will only be shared with third parties who perform tasks required to complete the purchase transaction. Examples of this include fulfilling orders and processing credit card payments.

Personal Information also includes information about your personal preferences, survey responses, and your transactions and interactions with us, if you are or have been a Member or you have provided this type of information to us.

**True and Current Information:**  If and when you do provide Personal Information, you are required to provide true, current, complete and accurate Personal Information and we have the right to cancel, terminate and/or revoke your right to use our Site, your status as a Member and delete any entry you make, if we have reason to believe information you provide to us is or may be false, fraudulent, inconsistent with this Privacy Policy or in violation of the [ **Terms of Use**](http://www.patheos.com/Terms-of-Use.html). Your use and continued use of our Site indicates your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and of the collection, use, disclosure, maintenance, management and storage of your Personal Information as described herein.

**Who May Use our Site:**  Our Site is not intended or designed to attract users under the age of 13. Only people age 13 or older are permitted to register as a Member. People under the age of 13 may browse our Site for educational and informational purposes, but are not allowed access to Member exclusive features such as creating a Member profile, participating in forums or chat rooms, or posting reviews. If you are under 13, do not send us or make available any Personal Information and do not attempt to register as a Member on our Site. Parents and guardians are asked to instruct their children under age 13 not to provide any Personal Information, including through the "contact us" link on our Site. Parents and guardians are asked to instruct their children under age 18 not to register or attempt to register to become a Member.

Our Site is intended for users located primarily in the United States. Users from other countries are advised to use common sense when disclosing Personal Information to our Site. By sending us Personal Information you consent to the application of U.S. law and to the use and disclosure of your information consistent with this Privacy Policy. If you are located outside of the U.S. and you use or attempt to use our Site, you do so at your own risk and you are responsible for compliance with all applicable local, national laws rules and regulations and, if applicable, international treaties, that apply to you and you are also deemed to have consented to the collection, storage, processing and use of your Personal Information in the United States.

**Information Collected and Used by our Site.**  We may use Personal Information to authenticate Members and to send notifications to our Members relating to the Service. Our Site also collects other Personal Information, including, but not limited to: personal interests, gender, age, education and occupation in order to assist Members in finding and communicating with each other and in order to customize offers and target communications to our Members. The Personal Information you supply allows us and/or our third party service providers to respond to your requests and to provide a variety of services on or associated with the Site.

Our Site also logs information including IP address, aggregate user data (which will not contain any Personal Information as it relates to a single visitor), browser type, and similar technical information regarding your computer, network and browser. This data is used to manage our Site, track usage and improve the Site. We may share this information with third-parties to provide more relevant services, tools, resources, Content and advertisements to Members, as well as for operational purposes. User and Member IP addresses are recorded for security and monitoring purposes.

Our primary service provider for collecting and processing site data and behavior is Google.  You can find more information on Google’s processing activities, by clicking on the following link ([https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/)).  We have also entered into Data Processing Amendments with third-party data and advertising partners, where necessary, to ensure compliance with all relevant local, national, and international regulations.

The profiles of our Members, including Members' pictures and screen names are displayed to other Members in order to facilitate Member interaction among Members on our Site. Members' full names and email addresses are never directly revealed to other Members by us. Members can also communicate with other Members through the Site without disclosing email addresses.

We may use Members' email addresses to send updates regarding the Site. Users may choose not to receive email of this type by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link in received emails and electing to unsubscribe from all mailings on the unsubscribe page.

From time to time we or a third party may sponsor a survey, promotion, sweepstakes or contest on our Site. You will generally need to be a Member to participate and you may be asked to provide certain Personal Information in order to do so. You will be notified at the time your Personal Information is requested and collected during your participation as to which entity is collecting the Personal Information. Information you provide to or for a third party, even if provided to us simultaneously (for example, in a joint promotion) is governed by their privacy policies and practices not ours and you should inquire about their policies and practices so you are aware of and agree to the manner in which they handle and treat any Personal Information you make available to them. We may also share your information with our business or promotional partners, with a subsequent entity that acquires or is merged with our business or with creditors and we may share Personal Information to certain advertising partners from which you have explicitly requested to receive information. We reserve the right to transfer Personal Information to a successor in interest that acquires rights to that information as a result of the sale of our Site or substantially all of its assets to that successor in interest.

In addition, we may from time to time, transfer or merge your Personal Information collected online to our offline databases. We may also combine Personal Information we collect online with information available from other sources, including information received from our advertisers and promotional partners. This Privacy Policy remains applicable to your Personal Information for as long as your Personal Information is in our possession, even if you terminate or discontinue your use of our Site and you acknowledge and agree you will be bound by its terms.

As noted above with regards to Google’s Data Activities on our site(s) as well as others across the web, the following resources may be helpful for you in understanding, changing, updating, and maintaining your profile data with Google.  These pages provide you with detailed information and give you control over your data with Google:

Myaccount.google.com

Myactivity.google.com

Privacy.google.com

**Use of Cookies by our Site and by Third Party Advertisers.**  Our Site uses cookies to store visitors' preferences and record session information, for purposes including ensuring that visitors are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize Content based on browser type and user profile information. You may be able to configure your browser to accept or reject all or some cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set - each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences - however, you must enable cookies from our Site in order to use most functions on our Site.

Advertisements appearing on our Site may be delivered to users and Members by a third party advertiser. Such third party advertisers may use cookies that allow the advertiser's server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, the third party advertiser's servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked on. This information allows a third party advertiser to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you.  **Please note that this Privacy Policy only covers the use of cookies by us on our Site and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers or third parties, even if an advertisement appears on our Site.**

In addition, BN Media, or data providers we have engaged, use cookies to enable you to receive customized ads (either on our site(s) or in our outbound marketing efforts on other sites and platforms), content or services, and to provide BN Media with certain information that enhances and enriches the user experience and our ability to understand our audience and inform our content and marketing strategy. No PII is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your e-mail address in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies, please go to [http://www.privacychoice.org/companies](http://www.beliefnet.com/About-Us/,\]%20http:/www.privacychoice.org/companies) and [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

You can opt out of our in-app behavioral targeted advertising by changing the settings on your mobile device. 

On Apple devices, the setting may be under Settings-Privacy-Advertising-Limit Ad Tracking. On Android devices, the setting may be under Settings-Account & Sync-Google-Ads-Opt Out of Interest-Based Ads.  For further information, please go to the following links with device-specific opt-out instructions.

iOS - [https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074)  
Android - [https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

Third party advertisements displayed on the Site may also contain cookies set by Internet advertising companies or advertisers. BN Media does not control these cookies and Users of the Site should check the privacy policy of the Internet advertising company or advertiser to see whether and how it uses cookies. (See Section C (Notice) 

below for more information on third party advertisements).

For personal, browser-specific information on how you can adjust your cookie and privacy settings and configurations on your devices, we’ve compiled the following list of resources:

_Internet Explorer_

[https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)

_Firefox_

https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored

_Chrome_

[https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform=Desktop&hl=en](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform=Desktop&hl=en)

_Safari_

https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US

**Pixels and Web Beacons:**

A pixel tag or web beacon is a tiny image inserted in a webpage and used to record the number and types of views for that page. BN Media may allow third party pixel tags or similar technology to be present on the Site for purposes of advertising, providing services or data and statistics collection. We also may use this type of technology in order to recognize Users and assess traffic patterns, and we may include pixel tags/web beacons in our e-mail messages, including newsletters, in order to understand the time and date of when a User has opened an e-email and when he/she has utilized a link within the e-mail to visit a website. These pixel tags/web beacons do not contain PII. Users wishing to disable our pixel tags/web beacons should do so by turning images “off” in their email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see your e-mail client for more information.

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we or a data provider we have engaged may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable customized ads or content. No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies, please go to [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

Uses of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies:

**Our uses of such technologies fall into the following general categories:**

  1. Operationally Necessary. We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies that are necessary to the operation of our sites, services, applications, and tools. This includes technologies that allow you access to our sites, services, applications, and tools; that are required to identify irregular site behavior, prevent fraudulent activity and improve security; or that allow you to make use of our functions such as shopping-carts, saved search, or similar functions;
  2. Performance Related. We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies to assess the performance of our websites, applications, services, and tools, including as part of our analytic practices to help us understand how our visitors use our websites, determine if you have interacted with our messaging, determine whether you have viewed an item or link, or to improve our website content, applications, services, or tools;
  3. Functionality Related. We may use cookies, web beacons, or other similar technologies that allow us to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing or using our sites, services, applications, or tools. This may include identifying you when you sign into our sites or keeping track of your specified preferences, interests, or past items viewed so that we may enhance the presentation of content on our sites;
  4. Advertising or Targeting Related.  We may use first-party or third-party cookies and web beacons to deliver content, including ads relevant to your interests, on our sites or on third party sites.  This includes using technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements and content that have been delivered to you, such as whether you have clicked on an advertisement. This information enables us to tailor our advertisements on third-party platforms like Facebook, Google, and other buying platforms and ensures that we can serve and target relevant ads to users on behalf of us and our advertising partners.

Third Party Ad and Service Provider Disclosures and Resources

Certain of our Third-party Advertisement and Data Service Providers have provided resources and disclosures to help you understand their positions in our site, data, and privacy framework.  Below are those disclosures and resources:

_Exponential_

 Subject to your consent, Exponential Interactive, Inc collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. You may change your consent decision at any time via OneTrust.com. For more details including access requests and complaints, review their [privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via [privacy@exponential.com](mailto:privacy@exponential.com).

_Criteo_

The purpose of Criteo Email is to find visitors of Criteo advertising clients’ properties (websites, apps and newsletters) and send them personalized emails. Criteo uses cookies to single out users and then personalize ads based on their browsing experience. To learn more or opt out of Criteo Email [click here](http://privacy.criteoemail.com/us/privacy-policy.html) 

(link to Criteo privacy policy at [http://privacy.criteoemail.com/us/privacy-policy.html](http://privacy.criteoemail.com/us/privacy-policy.html))

**Links.**  Our Site may provide links to other Web sites or resources. These links are for your convenience only and are not under our control. You acknowledge and agree that BN Media is not responsible for such external Web sites or resources, and neither BN Media nor our Site endorses any such Web site, its use or contents and is not responsible or liable for any content, advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such Web sites or resources. You agree that neither BN Media nor our Site shall be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage, viruses or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with your use of or reliance on any such content, goods or services available on such external Web sites or resources. In the event you decide to access or use any of these other Web sites or resources, you agree you do so at your own risk.

**Safety Tips.**  Our Site makes it easy to express yourself, connect with friends and make new ones, but please remember that what you post could embarrass you or expose you to danger. Here are some common sense guidelines that you should follow when using our Site and the Public Areas on our Site:

  * Don't forget that your profile and the Site's forums are public spaces. Don't provide Member Content to others or post anything you wouldn't want the world to know (e.g., your phone number, address, IM screen name, or specific whereabouts). Avoid posting anything that would make it easy for a stranger (or anyone else you may not want) to find you.
  * If you feel someone's behavior is inappropriate, illegal or offensive, react. Report it to our Site or the authorities.
  * Don't mislead people into thinking that you're older or younger or are someone you are not.
  * Don't get hooked by a phishing scam. Phishing is a method commonly used by criminals to obtain personal information, such as your username and password, by pretending to be a Web site or a company that you trust.

You agree that neither BN Media nor our Site shall be responsible or liable, either directly or indirectly, for Member Content you provide or make available or any thing you post or of the consequences of your actions. In the event you decide to reveal information about yourself or others that may expose you to danger or any harm you do so at your own risk.

**Marketing & Contact Preferences/Opt-out /Updating or Removing Information.** At various points during the Member registration process, you may be asked to indicate your willingness to allow us to communicate with you, share Personal Information collected online with third parties that are not related to our Site, or receive updates or notifications regarding the Site. We will honor your preferences, except as necessary to communicate with you regarding our Terms of Use, including this Privacy Policy, transactions or your Member profile, Member Content, postings or for customer service purposes (e.g., in response to your inquiries). At any time, however, you may (a) stop the receipt of a promotional email by clicking on an "unsubscribe" hyperlink contained in any promotional emails we send you, or (b) change your email preferences. Please allow BN Media a reasonable time to modify your preferences. Even after removal of PII and User Content by you or BN Media, PII and User Content may still be viewable in cached and archived pages or if another User has stored your User Content.

**Security.**  We maintain reasonable physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect your Personal Information and while no data transmission which is wireless or mobile or over the Internet is completely secure, we have and will continue to use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the protection of your Personal Information. Unfortunately, no Internet transaction is 100% secure, but we attempt to take reasonable measures to protect your Personal Information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. However, the Site cannot insure or warrant the security of that information.

Member accounts on our Site are secured by Member-created passwords. Our Site takes precautions to insure that Member account information is kept private. We restrict access to Member information to those employees who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel and technical staff.

SSL, an industry standard, is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. Since any information you provide to us on the Site will be transmitted using a secure connection, if your Web browser cannot support this level of security, you will not be able to make a purchase on our Site. The most recent versions of Safari, Firefox and Internet Explorer® andChrome can support a secure connection and can be downloaded for free from the Apple, Mozilla and Microsoft website respectively.

Additionally, as outlined in our DPAs (Data Processing Agreements) with third-party processors, BN Media will also be notified promptly by our third-party data processors of any breach of their systems so we can notify users immediately.

**Sharing and Disclosure of Information our Site Collects**. We have the rights to use any information you voluntarily submit to us. Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose Personal Information to any third party unless we believe that disclosure is necessary: (1) to conform to legal requirements or to respond to a subpoena, search warrant, request from law enforcement or other legal process received by our Site, whether or not a response is required by applicable law; (2) to enforce our Site's Terms of Use or to protect our rights; (3) to protect the safety of the public, our personnel, users of the Site, Members and/or others; and/or (4) as disclosed or notified to you, whether in our Terms of Use, including, this Privacy Policy, or otherwise on or in connection with your use of our Site.

**Contacting the Site or BN Media.  **If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at: [ **feedback@patheos.com**](mailto:feedback@patheos.com?subject=General%20Inquiry) or by mailing in to BN Media, LLC, 2037 Laskin Road, Virginia Beach, VA 23454, Attn: Jeremy McGee, BN Media Internet Privacy Officer
